<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>DART</title>
    <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu" />
    <updated>2021-01-25T11:50:42-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Hanna</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu</id>

    <entry>
        <title>DART Monthly Webinar // First Steps toward a Data Washing Machine</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2021-jan-27/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2021-jan-27/</id>
            <category term="DART Webinars"/>

        <updated>2021-01-25T11:50:42-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Title: First Steps toward a Data Washing Machine Presenter: John Talburt and David Ussery Date presented: January 27, 2021 Data&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Title:</strong> First Steps toward a Data Washing Machine<br><strong>Presenter:</strong> John Talburt and David Ussery<br><strong>Date presented:</strong> January 27, 2021</p>
<p> </p>
<!-- <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 70%;"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="600" height="300" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" id="kaltura_player" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1315742/sp/131574200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/40133072/partner_id/1315742?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_ld7rgdq8&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto&amp;flashvars[localizationCode]=en&amp;flashvars[leadWithHTML5]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.position]=left&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.clickToClose]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.layout]=vertical&amp;flashvars[chapters.thumbnailRotator]=false&amp;flashvars[streamSelector.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[EmbedPlayer.SpinnerTarget]=videoHolder&amp;flashvars[dualScreen.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[hotspots.plugin]=1&amp;flashvars[Kaltura.addCrossoriginToIframe]=true&amp;&amp;wid=1_p8oswqr5" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allow="autoplay *; fullscreen *; encrypted-media *" sandbox="allow-forms allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-top-navigation allow-pointer-lock allow-popups allow-modals allow-orientation-lock allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-presentation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation" frameborder="0" title="Kaltura Player" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<div> -->
<p>Data has a life cycle from planning to acquiring, cleansing, storing &amp; sharing, integrating, application, and disposing. While AI and machine learning have taken the application of data to new levels, the other phases remain largely manually mediated processes. The research goal for the Data Life Cycle and Curation thrust is to develop fully automated processes for the other phases of the data life cycle. The presentation today describes some of the progress of the research finding ways to automate data cleansing and data integration phases of the data life cycle.</p>
<p><strong>Presenter's Bios: </strong><br><strong>Dr. John Talburt, </strong>IQCP, CDMP is the Acxiom Chair of Information Quality at the University of Arkansas at Little Rock (UALR). Dr. Talburt also serves as coordinator of the Computer and Information Sciences PhD Program, and Executive Director of the Center for Advanced Research in Entity Resolution and Information Quality. In addition, Dr. Talburt is a member of the U.S. Technical Advisory Group to the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) Technical Committee 184, Subcommittee 4, Working Group 13 developing the ISO 8000 Industrial Data Quality Standard. Dr. Talburt is also the lead consultant for Data Quality Management and Data Governance for Noetic Partners, Inc. and previously served as the Chief Scientist for Black Oak Analytics, Inc., an Arkansas-based company specializing in data quality and entity identity information management solutions. Prior to his appointment at UA Little Rock he was the leader for research and development and product innovation at Acxiom Corporation, a global leader in information management and customer data integration. Professor Talburt is an inventor for several patents related to customer data integration and the author of numerous research papers and articles on information quality and entity resolution.</p>
<p><strong>Dr. David Ussery</strong> has been working with bioinformatic analysis of bacterial genomes since the first sequence was published in 1995, and published one of the first text books in the field of Comparative Genomics. His team has published more than 200 papers, which have been cited more than 15,000 times, including two papers with more than a thousand citations. He has been a co-applicant on grants funded totaling more than $30 million, since 2010. His popular course on Comparative Genomics, taught at The Technical University of Denmark from 1997 -2015, is now taught in the Fall semesters at the University of Arkansas for Medical Sceinces (UAMS); one-week workshops based on this course have been held in North and South America, Europe, Asia, and Africa. Prof. Usseryhas collaborative projects with groups in Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, The Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, and the UK, as well as in the U.S. Learn more about Dr. Ussery's work here: <a href="https://armoneyandpolitics.com/unlocking-the-human-genome-dr-david-ussery-uams/">https://armoneyandpolitics.com/unlocking-the-human-genome-dr-david-ussery-uams/</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/privacy-policy/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/privacy-policy/</id>

        <updated>2020-11-05T16:29:51-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The University of Arkansas and the Arkansas Economic Development Commission are committed to safeguarding the privacy of all personal data&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The University of Arkansas and the Arkansas Economic Development Commission are committed to safeguarding the privacy of all personal data provided by students, employees, alumni, and other constituents, as well as contractors (collectively “<strong>data subjects</strong>”).</p>
<p>Effective May 25, 2018, the European Union (“<strong>EU</strong>”) General Data Protection Regulation (“<strong>GDPR</strong>”) places additional obligations on organizations that control or process personally identifiable information about persons in Europe. The GDPR is designed to protect the privacy of data concerning a natural person that is collected or processed in or transferred out of the EU, and to regulate the data privacy practices of entities that offer goods or services in the EU. In its capacity as a data controller, the University collects, uses, and discloses data subjects’ information according to the following policy. </p>
<p>The GDPR applies to entities both inside and outside the EU. In addition, the regulations apply to data about anyone present in the EU, regardless of whether they are a citizen or permanent resident of an EU country; for example, GDPR includes U.S. persons when their personal data is collected, stored and used in the EU or transferred from the EU.</p>
<p>The GDPR defines “<strong>personal data</strong>” as follows:</p>
<p>“…any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“data subject”); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier (including information that is manually or automatically read, such as an IP address) or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.”</p>
<p>Please visit the University of Arkansas Privacy Policy page for more information on how the University of Arkansas uses, manages, and protects personal data that may be subject to the GDPR.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.uark.edu/privacy-policy/gdpr.php">https://www.uark.edu/privacy-policy/gdpr.php</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on how the Arkansas Economic Development Commission uses, manages, and protects personal data, please visit:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.arkansasedc.com/cookie-policy">https://www.arkansasedc.com/cookie-policy</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This privacy policy is intended to disclose to you our privacy practices in a manner that is easy to understand. If there is something you do not understand about our privacy practices, please feel free to contact Arkansas Economic Development Commission at <a href="mailto:info@arkansasedc.com">info@arkansasedc.com</a> or the University of Arkansas at <a href="mailto:uagdpr@uark.edu">uagdpr@uark.edu</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DART Monthly Webinar // Coordinated Cyber Infrastructure</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-nov-18/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-nov-18/</id>
            <category term="DART Webinars"/>

        <updated>2020-11-20T12:29:26-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Title: DART Cyber Infrastructure Resources Presenter: Fred Prior, Chris Angel, David Chaffin, and Pawel Wolinski Date presented: November 18, 2020&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Title:</strong> DART Cyber Infrastructure Resources<br><strong>Presenter:</strong> Fred Prior, Chris Angel, David Chaffin, and Pawel Wolinski<br><strong>Date presented:</strong> November 18, 2020</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 70%;"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="600" height="300" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" id="kaltura_player" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1315742/sp/131574200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/40133072/partner_id/1315742?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_ld7rgdq8&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto&amp;flashvars[localizationCode]=en&amp;flashvars[leadWithHTML5]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.position]=left&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.clickToClose]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.layout]=vertical&amp;flashvars[chapters.thumbnailRotator]=false&amp;flashvars[streamSelector.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[EmbedPlayer.SpinnerTarget]=videoHolder&amp;flashvars[dualScreen.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[hotspots.plugin]=1&amp;flashvars[Kaltura.addCrossoriginToIframe]=true&amp;&amp;wid=1_p8oswqr5" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allow="autoplay *; fullscreen *; encrypted-media *" sandbox="allow-forms allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-top-navigation allow-pointer-lock allow-popups allow-modals allow-orientation-lock allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-presentation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation" frameborder="0" title="Kaltura Player" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<div>
<p>Dr. Fred Prior, Dr. Chris Angel, Dr. David Chaffin, and Dr. Pawel Wolinski will present an overview of the Coordinated Cyber Infrastructure efforts on the DART project, including providing secure, distributed, agile, scalable, and on-demand services. This presentation will feature a demonstration using simple, "real-world" data science examples within the Arkansas Research Platform including: DART GitLab repository, Globus file transfer, and Pinnacle-portal.</p>
<p><strong>Presenter's Bios: </strong><br><strong><a href="https://uams-triprofiles.uams.edu/profiles/display/1588682" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">Dr. Fred Prior</a></strong> is Professor and Inaugural chair of the Department of Biomedical Informatics and Professor of Radiology at the University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences (UAMS). Dr. Prior has over 30 years of R&amp;D experience in industry and academia, focused on the design of advanced medical information management and imaging technologies. He has held senior management positions in a variety of R&amp;D environments ranging from Silicon Valley startups to major multi-national corporations in the US and Europe. Dr. Prior’s research interests include cancer informatics, radiomics, and neuroimaging informatics. He serves as principle investigator and director of the US National Cancer Institute’s Cancer Imaging Archive project and is the lead PI of an NCI ITCR team exploring the integration of radiomics and pathomics. Additionally, Dr. Prior directs informatics efforts for the UAMS Translational Research Institute and Pediatric Clinical Trial Network. </p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre"><strong>Dr. Christopher Angel</strong> is the Technical Lead at the Center for Advanced Spatial Technologies at the University of Arkansas (UAF) and has 12 years of experience in researching and leading development for spatio-temporal software applications, data management pipelines, and CI/CD strategies in both the public and private sectors to contribute to or create products and workflows contemporary to industry standards and cutting edge research. His primary focus has been on data management, analytics, and distribution techniques for a wide variety of use cases, from simple ETL applications to large scale photogrammetric workflows. Dr. Angel has led multiple teams in improving automation workflows and collaborative efficiency through source control management including code quality enforcement and reviews, and agile/scrum planning strategies. Managed deliverables have involved an array of languages and technologies including frontend/backend techniques in python, php, and nodejs; database interactions with SQL and NoSQL platforms; and containerization pipelines for automated testing and deployment (CI/CD). </p>
<p><strong>Dr. David Chaffin</strong> has degrees in Mechanical Engineering and a Ph.D. in Engineering Science, and has 40 years experience in computational engineering and high performance computing in government and academia, including the last 11 years at the<br>University of Arkansas (UAF) as Associate Director and Director of AHPPC.</p>
<p><strong>Dr. Pawel Wolinski</strong> is the Senior System Administrator at the Arkansas High Performance Computing Center and an Adjunct Professor in the Computer Science Department at the University of Arkansas (UAF). He holds a degree in Computer Science from UAF. He has several years of experience teaching at the undergraduate and graduate levels. His areas of interest include parallel distributed file systems, virtualization, kernel programming.  </p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DART Annual All-hands Meeting</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/annual-meeting/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/annual-meeting/</id>
            <category term="Events"/>

        <updated>2020-11-05T16:16:29-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The Annual All-hands Meeting and Poster Competition should be attended by all project faculty, students, industry partners, administrative committee members,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The Annual All-hands Meeting and Poster Competition should be attended by all project faculty, students, industry partners, administrative committee members, evaluators, and external advisory board members.</p>
<p>The annual meeting provides an opportunity for the project members to share their progress with the External Advisory Board and the Industry Advisory Board, as well as members of the Science Advisory Committee.</p>
<p>The year 1 Annual Meeting will take place over two days during May 2021. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Stay in Touch with DART</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/stay-in-touch-with-dart/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/stay-in-touch-with-dart/</id>

        <updated>2020-11-05T16:16:23-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Are you interested in Data Analytics that are Robust and Trusted? Join our email list to stay in the know&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Are you interested in Data Analytics that are Robust and Trusted? </strong><br>Join our email list to stay in the know about this project and the growing array of tools and research that are generated by research faculty and their students.</p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="900px" height="1200px" style="border: none; max-width: 100%; max-height: 100vh;" src="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=xELHeRzmpU--iaPLVmqA0SUdGkh-5HdBljNSQuipMy5UNEo4R0k5VkJSWTRBMko3N0E2T1JEMTRSUy4u&amp;embed=true" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" msallowfullscreen=""> </iframe></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DART Monthly Webinar // Welcome to DART, presented by Dr. Jackson Cothren (Oct 28 2020) </title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-oct-28/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-oct-28/</id>
            <category term="DART Webinars"/>

        <updated>2020-11-20T12:26:42-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Title: Welcome to DART Presenter: Jackson Cothren Date presented: October 28, 2020 Dr. Jackson Cothren will present an overview of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Title:</strong> Welcome to DART <br><strong>Presenter:</strong> Jackson Cothren<br><strong>Date presented:</strong> October 28, 2020</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 70%;"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="600" height="300" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" id="kaltura_player" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1315742/sp/131574200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/40133072/partner_id/1315742?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_o4meqceh&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto&amp;flashvars[localizationCode]=en&amp;flashvars[leadWithHTML5]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.position]=left&amp;flashvars[sideBarContainer.clickToClose]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[chapters.layout]=vertical&amp;flashvars[chapters.thumbnailRotator]=false&amp;flashvars[streamSelector.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[EmbedPlayer.SpinnerTarget]=videoHolder&amp;flashvars[dualScreen.plugin]=true&amp;flashvars[hotspots.plugin]=1&amp;flashvars[Kaltura.addCrossoriginToIframe]=true&amp;&amp;wid=1_v5ca8azv" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allow="autoplay *; fullscreen *; encrypted-media *" sandbox="allow-forms allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-top-navigation allow-pointer-lock allow-popups allow-modals allow-orientation-lock allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-presentation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation" frameborder="0" title="Kaltura Player"></iframe></div></div>
<p>Dr. Jackson Cothren will present an overview of the National Science Foundation-funded EPSCoR Track 1 award entitled, "Data Analytics that are Robust and Trusted (DART): From Smart Curation to Socially Aware Decision Making."</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Presenter's Bio:</strong><a target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://nam11.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcast.uark.edu%2Fdirectory%2Findex%2Fuid%2Fjcothre%2Fname%2FJackson%2BDavid%2BCothren%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7Chlford%40uark.edu%7Cfb0f53d0245a41a6ec5608d87a90a0d3%7C79c742c4e61c4fa5be89a3cb566a80d1%7C0%7C0%7C637394108870547283%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=JmzQuL5HPIXkBo8BzTVpelT4ro%2BTKG3al8qJsxLOA2M%3D&amp;reserved=0">  Dr. Jackson Cothren</a> is the Science Director of the DART project and a CoLead in the Coordinated Cyberinfrastructure Research Theme. Cothren is a professor in the Department of Geosciences at the University of Arkansas and leads both the Center for Advanced Spatial Technologies and the Arkansas High Performance Computing Center. Dr. Cothren's research interests include various aspects of digital photogrammetry and computer vision including non-traditional sensor modeling, feature extraction and matching for orientation, surface generation, adjustment models and integration with enterprise-scale geospatial information systems.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Monthly Webinar Series</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/monthly-webinar-schedule/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/monthly-webinar-schedule/</id>
            <category term="Events"/>
            <category term="DART Webinars"/>

        <updated>2021-01-25T10:57:49-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The DART Monthly Webinar Series provides an opportunity for project faculty and students to share short presentations about their work&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>
<div>
<div>The DART Monthly <span class="highlight selected">Webinar Series provides an opportunity for project faculty and students to share </span>short presentations about their work followed by open discussion and questions. Webinar topics will rotate between project management items like reporting and overviews of DART as a project, as well as specific research topics, important research results, and more. The agenda for these webinars includes: <span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" data-ogsc="black">10 min (welcome and introduction); </span><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" data-ogsc="black">25 min (presentation); 2</span><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" data-ogsc="black">5 min (questions).</span><span lang="en" style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" data-ogsc="black"> </span></div>
<div> </div>
<div>Would you like to present? Please email <a href="mailto:hlford@uark.edu">hlford@uark.edu</a> to secure your date!</div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Webinar FAQs:</strong></div>
<ul>
<li>Webinars will be hosted using the University of Arkansas Zoom account which requires that you have a Zoom account to join (free accounts are available <a href="https://nam11.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Ffreesignup%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7Chlford%40uark.edu%7Ccb099b72d17b4c7ecb9808d87a890427%7C79c742c4e61c4fa5be89a3cb566a80d1%7C0%7C0%7C637394076780531346%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=aYE0ijsuZDFgIsdpedinrNjXqMZYeh3GmH3RxT9G4uU%3D&amp;reserved=0" originalsrc="https://zoom.us/freesignup/" shash="f9SCi3kayPGuy1zCNaO7qWZQWDFZ2B8OeKsA8U+mkWDuzQEtdazdxl6l5Y7SL36V6/CNDokXf/FrPAMvbKHyuALZEGfE2u2LMVaPp5VeqpbUotV9ud3IlTIytWv0rRufmJpxfDY4LlTyx2INg8/wga8A2c7fpIfSQGZAwb6/c+o=" id="LPlnk">https://zoom.us/freesignup/</a>).</li>
<li data-ogsb="white"><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">All webinars will be recorded and made available after presentation. Links will be posted on this site.</span></li>
<li data-ogsb="white">If you would like to receive notices for future webinars are not a DART student or faculty member, sign up <a href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/stay-in-touch-with-dart/">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="post__toc">
<h3>Webinars are organized by Calendar Year</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#2021">2021</a></li>
<li><a href="#2020">2020</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="2021">2021 Webinars</h3>
<div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>January 27</strong>   |   <a href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2021-jan-27/">First Steps toward a Data Washing Machine, presented by Data Curation and Life Cycle CoLeads</a></span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>February 24</strong> |   <a href="#">Social Awareness, presented by Social Awareness CoLeads</a></span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>March 31</strong>   |   Social Media and Networks, presented by Social Media and Networks CoLeads</span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>April 28</strong>   |   Learning and Prediction, presented by Learning and Predication CoLeads</span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>May 17-20 (TBD)</strong>   |   Annual All-Hands Meeting</span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>June (TBD)</strong>   |   Education and Outreach, presented by Education and Outreach CoLeads</span></p>
<p data-ogsb="white"> </p>
</div>
<div> </div>
</div>
<h3 id="2020">2020 Webinars</h3>
<div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>October 28</strong>   |   <a href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-oct-28/">Welcome to DART, presented by Dr. Jackson Cothren</a></span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>November 18 </strong> |   <a href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/dart-webinar-2020-nov-18/">Coordinated Cyberinfrastructure, presented by CI CoLeads </a></span></p>
</div>
<div>
<p data-ogsb="white"><span data-ogsc="black"><strong>December</strong>   |   No webinar</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>FAQs</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/faqs/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/faqs/</id>
            <category term="FAQs"/>

        <updated>2020-11-03T08:40:19-06:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="post__toc">
<h3>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqja6p71k">Project Contacts</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjb6h61m">Funding</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjmhou1o">Project Organizational Structure</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjodgh2v">Roles and Responsibilities</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjodgh30">NSF-related Project Roles</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjodgh31">Research Theme Roles</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqjodgh32">Other Project Roles</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqnsd6b72">Personnel Changes and Vacancies</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqnsd6b73">Project Reporting</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1elqnsd6b74">Acknowledgement of NSF Support/Disclaimer</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqja6p71k">Project Contacts</h2>
<p><strong>Arkansas Economic Development Commission (AEDC; also known as Central Office): </strong>Staff includes Steve Stanley, Jennifer Fowler and Cathy Ma. The central EPSCoR office at AEDC is the primary awardee and will manage all project related communication with NSF. Any items that need to be discussed with the NSF program office need to go through AEDC. AEDC will also serve as a liaison between the SSC and Management Team/SAC.</p>
<p>Steve Stanley, <a href="mailto:SStanley@ArkansasEDC.com&lt;br&gt;">SStanley@ArkansasEDC.com</a><br>Jennifer Fowler, <a href="mailto:JFowler@ArkansasEDC.com&lt;br&gt;">JFowler@ArkansasEDC.com</a><br>Cathy Ma, <a href="mailto:cma@arkansasedc.com">cma@arkansasedc.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Science &amp; Research Lead Contacts:</strong> Staff includes Jackson Cothren and Hanna Ford. Both are located at the University of Arkansas, Fayetteville and serve as the primary organizational lead for the science and research program.</p>
<p>Jackson Cothren, <a href="mailto:jcothre@uark.edu">jcothre@uark.edu</a><br>Hanna Ford, <a href="mailto:hlford@uark.edu">hlford@uark.edu</a></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqjb6h61m">Funding</h2>
<p>This is not a grant. This is a cooperative agreement and is performance-based. Per DART award Terms and Conditions, NSF reserves the right to phase-out, suspend or terminate this cooperative agreement at any time should progress be deemed unsatisfactory. Both the project as a whole and the performance of individuals are evaluated annually.</p>
<p><br><strong>Eligible organizations and institutions:</strong> Funded collaborations are limited to those within the EPSCoR jurisdiction (Arkansas). For more details, please see: NSF 19-580, Section II. Program Description, <a href="https://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2019/nsf19580/nsf19580.htm#pgm_desc_txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Item B. Eligible Organizations and Information</a>. </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqjmhou1o">Project Organizational Structure</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/media/posts/3/project-organization-chart-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/media/posts/3/responsive/project-organization-chart-2-xs.png 300w ,https://dart.cast.uark.edu/media/posts/3/responsive/project-organization-chart-2-sm.png 480w ,https://dart.cast.uark.edu/media/posts/3/responsive/project-organization-chart-2-md.png 768w"  alt="" width="900" height="506"></figure>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqjodgh2v">Roles and Responsibilities</h2>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1elqjodgh30">NSF-related Project Roles</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Program Director (PI)</strong>, Steve Stanley: Responsible for the overall statewide project management, which includes administration of the central office, overall management of science, outreach, and workforce development efforts, cyberinfrastructure, and evaluation, developing new funding opportunities to leverage or add support and linkage with other federal grants, and providing progress report to and communicating with NSF EPSCoR Office.</li>
<li><strong>Science Director (CoPI)</strong>, Jackson Cothren: Serves as executive director for the Science Steering Committee (Leadership Team). Oversees research activities within and across the topic areas ensuring that collaborative activities are ongoing, productive, and fall within the defined research goals of the project.</li>
<li>All other members submitted on the NSF proposal are listed as Sr. Personnel.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1elqjodgh31">Research Theme Roles</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Research Theme CoLead:</strong> A CoLead has two important administrative roles: 1) serve as liaison between SSC and the respective research theme faculty groups; 2) lead the respective research theme in maintaining synchronous progress across all activities within the research theme and integrated research themes, including but not limited to: coordinating meetings and distributing communications among research theme faculty members; communicating progress to the SSC; communicating upcoming or existing personnel vacancies to the SSC. The CoLead role is primarily an administrative role and does not include any additional resources or support.</li>
<li><strong>Research Theme Activity PI and CoPIs:</strong> Each research them includes several activities. For each activity there is one PI. The PI should communicate with the activity team regularly to ensure the project is performing satisfactorily. The PI should liaison with the research theme CoLead. In cases where multiple CoPIs lead a research theme activity, it is their collective responsibility to perform the duties of research theme activity PI.</li>
<li><strong>Research Theme Sr. Personnel:</strong> In each research theme activity, a number of faculty within that theme are assigned as senior personnel. They each have particular expertise and skills needed to accomplish the milestones in that activity. Faculty may be senior pesonnel in multiple activities and many also serve as PI or CoPI in other activities.</li>
<li><strong>Research Theme Liaison:</strong> Liaisons have the task of disseminating information between research themes. Individuals with this role have subject area expertise that is relevant in multiple themes and across multiple activities. While they are not necessarily responsible for milestones in their cross-theme activity, they should: 1) attend meetings and keep up with progress in that activity, and 2) inform their theme of relevant results and possible collaborations.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1elqjodgh32">Other Project Roles</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Science Steering Committee (SSC; also known as: Leadership Team):</strong> Comprised of CoLeads from each research theme. Provides oversight for the scientific aspects of the program and is responsible for ensuring research theme milestones and objectives are being met annually. The SSC is also responsible for participating in NSF Site Visits, annual conferences, and communicating progress to the external evaluation board and external evaluator via annual reports and presentations.The SSC works closely with the EAB, PI, and CoPI to provide technical and/or scientific guidance as lead researchers on the project. Each SSC member is responsible for at least one planned activity in Section 4.3 of the proposal, and is responsible for planning, execution, reporting, and dissemination via inter-institutional workshops.</li>
<li><strong>Management Team:</strong> Comprised of vice-provost level administrators from each campus receiving a subaward. The PI, CoPI, and Management Team are responsible for financial decisions and other administrative duties.</li>
<li><strong>Science Advisory Committee (SAC; also known as the Arkansas EPSCoR Steering Committee):</strong> Committee is composed of representatives from academia, government, and the private sector. The SAC selects the topical areas for each Track-1 Proposal, designates the fiscal agent/proposing organization as the responsible recipient for the RII Track-1 award, and must provide support for the Track-1 Proposal for NSF acceptance.</li>
<li><strong>External Advisory Board (EAB):</strong> The EAB will include researchers from peer and aspirant universities or national labs who serve as technical consultants providing recommendations on research progress and strategic and long-term sustainability planning during annual site visits. The EAB will serve a critical role in the seed grant program as well as in mentoring and commercialization efforts.</li>
<li><strong>Industry Advisory Board (IAB):</strong> The IAB members will serve as an intermediary between academia and industry. The IAB will include representatives from Arkansas industry sectors who will be impacted by DART research. Ex-officio members include the project Co-PI (to communicate scientific results), the project PI (to serve as the liaison to government and policy organizations), and members from related organizations like the Arkansas Center for Data Science and the Arkansas Research Alliance. The IAB will meet annually in conjunction with the Annual All-Hands Meeting, and they will meet quarterly to review results and recommend new areas of research and collaboration based on industry needs. One member of the IAB (rotating annually) will serve as a member of the EAB during site visits.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqnsd6b72">Personnel Changes and Vacancies</h2>
<ul>
<li>Personnel replacement should only be considered if a researcher has: 1) left their position; 2) has over-allocated their available research time and will not be able to fulfill their role in the project; or 3) is not performing satisfactorily.</li>
<li><strong>CoLead Vacancies:</strong> Suggestions for Research Theme CoLead replacements should be submitted via email to Steve Stanley (Project Director) at SStanley@ArkansasEDC.com, Jackson Cothren (Project Science Director) at jcothre@uark.edu; and copying Hanna Ford (DART Science Project Manager) hlford@uark.edu ; please include a short synopsis of their qualifications. The SSC should review all requests for CoLead replacement and make a recommendation to the AEDC Central Office for approval. The AEDC Cental Office will notify the Management Team, SAC, and NSF of the final decision.</li>
<li><strong>Sr. Personnel Vacancies:</strong> Suggestions for Sr. Personnel replacements should be submitted via email to Steve Stanley (Project Director) at SStanley@ArkansasEDC.com, Jackson Cothren (Project Science Director) at jcothre@uark.edu; and copying Hanna Ford (DART Science Project Manager) hlford@uark.edu; please include a short synopsis of their qualification. Requests for Sr. Personnel replacements will have to be reviewed and approved the AEDC Central Office if they are not a direct replacement (same institution and research theme activities). If the replacement is a direct replacement the DART PI and CoPI can approve this replacement. The AEDC Cental Office will notify the Management Team, SAC, and NSF of the final decision.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqnsd6b73">Project Reporting</h2>
<div class="card-body text-left">
<p class="card-text">All faculty are required to submit data to the project’s reporting website, ER Core (<a href="https://dartreporting.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dartreporting.org</a>). Annual reports are generated using the input provided in ER Core. Any information not submitted to ER Core will not be reported to NSF. Data collected includes but is not limited to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Project participants- faculty, graduate students, undergrads, postdocs, collaborators</li>
<li>Publications related to the project</li>
<li>Any additional proposals submitted during the project</li>
<li>Honors and awards to any project participant</li>
<li>Outreach activities</li>
<li>Patents related to the project</li>
<li>Startup companies related to the project</li>
<li>Presentations of project related data</li>
<li>Collaborations with people outside the project or related activities among participants that are not listed in the strategic plan</li>
<li>Other research products including data, databases, software, educational aids, instruments, equipment, etc.</li>
</ol>
<p>All project participants are also expected to participate in the AR EPSCoR annual conference. Graduate students, postdocs, and faculty participants are expected to participate in the annual retreat. Students will be expected to present their research at least once per year in a poster competition.</p>
<p>The project will be evaluated annually by a panel of external advisors and a contract external evaluator. The two culminating reports will be filed with NSF and the project will be expected to accept any feedback and incorporate changes as suggested.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1elqnsd6b74">Acknowledgement of NSF Support/Disclaimer</h2>
<p class="card-text">Acknowledgment of NSF Support/Disclaimer in compliance with <a href="https://www.nsf.gov/pubs/policydocs/pappg20_1/pappg_11.jsp#XIE">NSF PAPPG, Chapter XI – Other Post Award Requirements and Considerations, Section E. Publication/Distribution of Grant Materials, Item 4. Grantee Obligations.</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggested Acknowledgement: This material is based upon work supported by the National Science Foundation under <a href="https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1946391&amp;HistoricalAwards=false">Award No. OIA-1946391</a>.</li>
<li>Suggested Disclaimer: Any opinions, findings, and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the author(s) and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Science Foundation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Graduate Research Assistants (GRAs)</p>
<ul>
<li>For each year of funding we hope to support 40 graduate student stipends and tuition (either M.S. level or PhD level).</li>
<li>GRA funding will not be on the same subaward as your research funding. GRA funding will be paid to your Institution separately, as a standalone project to your institution at the beginning of each project year.</li>
<li>Graduate student funds are not available for re-allocation to other categories. Support will be provided for the number of graduate students assigned at each institution.</li>
<li>Students should be assigned to individual advisors at their home institution but may be co-advised by faculty at other institutions.</li>
<li>Advisors must identify students by name. If an advisor is not able to identify a student who can support the project, research theme CoLeads may reallocate the GRA slot to another advisor with a named student within the research theme.</li>
<li>Support for graduate students will only be provided for GRAs that can be identified by name at your institution. Please be prepared to supply this information to your Office of Sponsored Programs or equivalent at the beginning of each funding year.</li>
<li>If a GRA students graduates and/or leaves the project, PIs can name other students who are qualified to work on DART. PIs are required to notify AEDC and get approval before new students receive GRA funds.</li>
</ul>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Data Analytics that are Robust and Trusted</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hanna</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://dart.cast.uark.edu/about-dart/"/>
        <id>https://dart.cast.uark.edu/about-dart/</id>

        <updated>2020-11-05T16:15:51-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The growing array of tools - powerful high-level programming languages, distributed data storage and computation, visualization tools, statistical modeling, and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The growing array of tools - powerful high-level programming languages, distributed data storage and computation, visualization tools, statistical modeling, and machine learning - along with a staggering array of big data sources, has the potential to empower people to make better and more timely decisions in science, business, and society. However, there remain fundamental barriers to practical application and acceptance of data analytics, any one of which could derail or impede its full development and contributions.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Big data management:</strong> Before data streams and datasets can be used in the many kinds of learning models, they are often manually curated, or at the least, curated for a specific problem. We still rely on hosts of analysts to assess the content and quality of source data, engineer features, define and transform data models, annotate training data, and track data processes and movement.</li>
<li><strong>Security and privacy:</strong> Government agencies and private entities collect and integrate large amounts of data, process it in real-time, and deliver products or services based on these data to consumers and constituents. There are increasing worries that both the acquisition and subsequent application of big data analytics are not secure or well-managed. This can create a risk of privacy breaches, enable discrimination, and negatively impact diversity in our society.</li>
<li><strong>Model interpretability:</strong> Machine learning models often sacrifice interpretability for predictive power and are difficult to generalize beyond their training and test data. But interpretability and generalizability of trained models is critical in many decision-making systems and/or processes, especially when learning from multi-modal and heterogeneous big data sources. There is a continuing to need to better balance the predictive power of complex machine learning models with the strengths of statistical models to better configure deep learning models to allow humans to see the reasoning behind the predictions.</li>
</ul>
<p>DART research will systematically investigate key aspects of these three barriers and develop novel, integrated solutions to address them by operating as a true, multi-institution, multi-disciplinary data science research center, in which faculty and students from campuses across the state work together on targeted problems important to the research community and the economy of Arkansas.</p>
<h4>Participating Institutions | <span style="font-size: 16px; color: dimgrey;"> Project Component: </span><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #ed5252;"><i class="fas fa-square"></i> Education </span><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #a7c639;"><i class="fas fa-square"></i> Research </span><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #129dcd;"><i class="fas fa-square"></i> Education and Research </span></h4>
<div class="container-fluid"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="900" height="592" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="10px;" marginwidth="0" title="DART Collaborating Institutions" src="https://uark.maps.arcgis.com/apps/Embed/index.html?webmap=816ca6944c734cbb920b04cd37791b14&amp;extent=-97.9509,32.0503,-87.0964,37.5362&amp;zoom=true&amp;previewImage=false&amp;scale=true&amp;disable_scroll=true&amp;theme=light"></iframe></div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
